The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Little friend...
Give me my disciple's Soul Blood.
Okay ?
So fast !
May I know the name of Senior's disciple ?
My disciple
is Zhou Zihong.
Alright.
Junior will travel 1000 li
and leave the Soul Blood there.
Little friend doesn't need to worry.
I’ve heard from Zihong that
the three of them returned safely to the War God Shrine
thanks to your help.
Even if you possessed this body,
you helped Zihong to return.
That is why I will overlook this matter.
Forgive me Senior,
Junior promises to give you the Soul Blood
after I travel 1000 li.
1000 li
is a distance that I
can cross in a few breaths.
If I wanted to kill you,
then unless you escaped 10 000 li away,
it would be pointless.
Fine,
if you insist,
then go.
Senior,
as we agreed, here’s the Soul Blood.
Whether that woman lied to me or not,
it isn't worth offending a Nascent Soul cultivator
over some Soul Blood.
He may only be Middle stage Foundation Establishment
but he’s exceedingly cautious.
Luo River Sect
Burning Fire country
Suppress the Earth Fire !
Don’t let it leak out !
Let's do it together !
What happened ?
Who trespassed in the Alchemy Hall ?
We don't know who this thief is
but he disguised himself as a disciple of the sect.
He tried to steal the Heaven Separating Pill that was just refined.
Li Qiqing
Luo River Sect disciple
Late stage Foundation Establishment
The Heaven Separating Pill is unstable
and must be consumed within an hour.
Somehow, the thief knew our secret...
Luckily, Senior Sister Muwan was on duty and noticed.
Where’s Wan’er ?
Is she hurt ?
Senior Sister Muwan is unharmed.
She has already delivered the Heaven Separating Pill
to the Ancestor.
Good.
Let's split up,
we will catch this thief !
Even with my Ji Realm,
I’m no match for a Nascent Soul cultivator.
If she wanted to capture me,
I wouldn't be able to escape.
I can’t stay in the Burning Fire country.
Even if Lin Tao can get me a map in 10 days,
that plan can fail.
I saw in Ma Liang’s memories
that the Ravine Market holds the largest auctions here.
I'll see if I can find a map there.
His physique
matches the thief !
The thief is skilled in disguise !
Fellow cultivators,
what is wrong ?
You trespassed our sect’s restricted area.
Did you think that your disguise
would fool us again ?
You will die today !
Brother, stop !
Wan’er ?
Li Muwan
Luo River Sect disciple
Early stage Foundation Establishment
Brother, it’s not him.
The thief can change his appearance
but he couldn't have changed his aura to this extent.
This…
Fellow cultivator, forgive me.
I’m Li Qiqing of the Luo River Sect.
I apologize for the misunderstanding.
No problem.
Since it’s a misunderstanding,
how could I, Ma Liang, hold a grudge.
Young Master Ma,
are you heading to the Ravine Market ?
Maybe we can meet again.
Fellow cultivator,
I apologize for today’s incident.
We have urgent matters to deal with
so we’ll take our leave.
Continue the search !
Sun Youcai
Evil Devil Sect disciple
Late stage Foundation Establishment
Fellow cultivator,
this is a misunderstanding !
Fellow cultivator, I’m Sun Youcai of the Evil Devil Sect
I didn't want to follow you earlier,
but I had to.
The Luo River Sect is looking for me
and I can't beat them.
I had to hide !
They are still looking for me
but if I follow you
then I will be a lot safer.
Fellow cultivator,
I truly apologize for earlier.
This guy is really fast...
Are you going to the Ravine Market ?
He’s only Late stage Foundation Establishment
but his speed nearly matches that Nascent Soul woman’s.
Why don't we go together ? I know a lot of people there.
Fellow cultivator, we should travel together.
Does he have a movement artifact ?
Fellow cultivator,
what do you think ?
Alright,
I’ll trouble Brother Sun then.
It's weird,
this kid is only Middle stage Foundation Establishment
but even if I am Late stage,
I'm somehow afraid of him.
No problem.
Afterall, I used your help first.
I'll take care of everything.
May I ask
fellow cultivator's name ?
I’m Ma Liang
of the War God Shrine.
Brother Ma, there is a
a teleportation formation to the Ravine Market.
That's great,
let's go there first then.
Brother Ma, are you traveling alone ?
Yes.
Brother Ma,
the formation requires 3 spirit stones.
I will call a friend,
he should be nearby.
That way, we can share the cost
and save up on 1 spirit stone.
What do you think ?
Okay
Don't worry Brother Ma,
I will pay your share.
If not for you,
the Luo River Sect would've caught me.
Brother Ma,
the teleportation formation is close
even if this place looks barren.
Lately, the volcanoes of the Burning Gold Mountains
have been emitting black smoke.
I think it was last year
that the 4 sects’ Nascent Soul Ancestors
strengthened the seal.
This remote place
is perfect for killing someone.
With so many volcanoes
disposing of a body is easy.
You don't even need fire spells.
Brother Ma, what do you mean by that ?
This person's cultivation is higher than Sun Youcai’s.
He's Peak Late stage.
Li Yong
Evil Devil Sect disciple
Peak Late stage Foundation Establishment
He's likely the mastermind behind this.
Is that the fat sheep you were talking about ?
Senior Brother, it’s him.
I saw Li Muwan and her brother Li Qiqing
had a good impression of him.
If we refine his body into a puppet,
we'll be have a better chance
at infiltrating the Luo River Sect again.
You can die now, kid.
Die.
What the...?
The Earth Escape Technique ?
Devour that purple mist.
I don't even know if I can devour it
and he told me to eat it like that ?
Now’s my chance
to escape.
I give up ! I give up !
I swear I won’t try again !
It would benefit me if I can obtain
his Earth Escape Technique.
Killing a Foundation Establishment cultivator with a single word
isn’t the level of Core Formation or Nascent Soul.
The legends say that Soul Formation cultivators can control the ways of the heavens.
So killing in a single word
would make sense...
Am I really
being hunted by a Soul Formation cultivator ?
Why is it getting warm ?
Could it be…?
Master,
there’s immense spiritual energy in the lava.
The Burning Fire country is covered in volcanoes
and somehow I ended in this one...
How can creatures live in these volcanoes ?
If the Ancestors seal them every few years
then how did they miss this ?
I must leave quickly.
My Ji Realm attack failed !?
Hey, you're burning me !
Bye-bye Master !
This is bad !
This is…
the Fire spirit Beasts’ lair.
Why do they capture so many cultivators ?
This giant fire beast rivals Nascent Soul cultivation,
perhaps even stronger.
Why is the Heaven Defying Bead moving on its own ?
That ball of fire is devouring the cultivators...
That beast completed the whole fire element in one go.
Was it the Fire Spirit Beast King ?
The amount of elemental spiritual energy needed to complete each element of the Heaven Defying Bead increases each time. That is why Wang Lin managed to upgrade it at first by using dew but now had to unearth an entire root of spirit fruits and it barely progressed the wood element. The Fire Spirit Beast King was enough to completely fill the fire element.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?